Hey, you guys, what are you
doing tomorrow night?
Well, let
me see.
I believe I'm...
yes, falling asleep
in front of the TV.
My agent hooked me up
with six tickets
to a great play.
I could fall asleep at a play.
What is it?
It's a one-woman play called,
Why Don't You Like Me?
A Bitter Woman's Journey
Through Life.
That sounds interesting.
That does sound interesting.
I mean, to listen to a woman
complain for two hours.
I don't think it gets bett...
( snoring )
I know, I know.
We can drive, we can vote,
we can work.
What more do these broads want?
Well, you guys are going
to have a great time, I promise.
What? How
come you don't
have to go?
I wish I could,
but I just found out
that I have to be at work
really early the next day.
So I can't go.
But, you know, take
the extra ticket
and invite whoever you want.
Ooh, let's see, who do I hate?
Oh, sorry.
Hey, up we go.
All right.
Oh.
Can I ask you
a question?
Yeah.
Do you think
it's possible
for two friends
to fool around
and not have it be
a big deal?
No, I don't think
that ever works.
Why?
No reason.
No, no. Rachel?
Yeah?
Who do you want
to fool around with?
Nobody. Forget it.
( whispers ):
Maybe.
You can't.
Why?
( whispering )
Seriously, I did not understand
a word you just said.
In the hall.
All right.
You want to fool around
with Joey?
Yeah. You know what?
Ever since
I had that dream about him,
I can't get it
out of my head.
I mean, what's the big deal?
People do it all time.
Who? Who do you know
that are friends
that just fool around?
Okay, off the top of my head...
Don and Janet.
Who are they?
I, uh, I know them
from work.
Both of them?
No, one of them.
Which one?
I don't know.
What were the names I just said?
Rachel, things could get
incredibly complicated.
All right, all right, all right.
You're right.
I won't do anything
with Joey.
I just thought it would...
Okay, that would be
two cups of tarragon,
one pound of baking soda
and one red onion?
What the hell are you cooking?
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's D.O.A. ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ When the rain starts to pour ♪
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
♪ Like I've been there before ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
Hey.
You guys won't believe
what I have to do
for work today.
Yes, but Ross,
you chose a career
of talking
about dinosaurs.
There are these
two professors
who are joining
my department,
and I have to meet them here
and show them around campus.
What's so bad
about that?
Well, I just know they're going
to be couple of old windbags
wearing tweed jackets
with suede elbow patches.
Ross...
These aren't suede.
Excuse me.
I'm looking
for someone.
You don't by
any chance
know a Ross Geller?
No.
Hi.
Hi. I'm Ross Geller.
Oh, hi.
I'm Professor Wheeler.
Oh... oh, that's...
that's, that's nice.
It's good to meet you.
Thank you so much
for taking the time out
to show me around.
Oh, no, it's no big deal.
I mean, if I weren't doing this,
I'd just, you know,
be at the gym working out.
Is he going
to introduce us?
I think we're just
blurry shapes to him now.
By the way, I really
enjoyed your paper
on the connection between
geographic isolation
and rapid mutagenesis.
Oh...
I wrote that in one night.
20 bucks says they're
married within the month.
We should probably
get going.
Um, you know, we've got
a lot of ground to cover.
Oh, isn't there
another professor
that's supposed
to come with us?
I don't think so.
I'm pretty sure a Professor
Spafford from Cornell?
Well, he's
obviously late
and the rule in my class is,
if you can't come on time,
then don't come at all.
An option that many
of my students use.
Shall we?
You don't think
we should wait for him?
Oh, you know what?
He's a big boy.
I'm sure he'll find us,
okay?
Professor Geller?
Aw, damn it.
( beep )
WOMAN:
Hi, Joey. It's Jan Rogers.
Can't wait for
your party tonight.
Listen, I forgot your address.
Can you give me a call?
Thanks. Bye.
( humming tune )
Hey.
What's happening?
Yeah, it's a real shame
you can't make it
to that one-woman
show tonight.
Oh, I'd love to, but I got
to get up so early the next day.
You know me,
work comes first.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hi, Joey. It's Jan Rogers.
Can't wait for
your party tonight...
Stupid Jan Rogers!
You are having
a party tonight?!
Kind of having a thing
for the Days of Our Lives
people.
And you weren't
going to tell us?
How did you think you were going
to get away with that?
I do it every year.
You do that
every year?!
I didn't have
to tell you that.
God, I'm stupider than
Jan Rogers.
( gasps )
That's why you got us
tickets to that play.
To get rid of us.
Yeah.
And last year, is that why
you sent us to that
Medieval Times restaurant?
Yeah.
And the year before that
when you set up that nighttime
tour of that button factory?
I can't believe you guys
went for that one.
Joey, why wouldn't you invite us
to your parties?
You're fine, okay?
But everyone else acts
like an idiot
around famous people.
Well, then so just invite me.
Please, I was trying to be nice.
You're the worst one.
Oh, Joey, come on, please,
please, let me come.
I will behave, I promise.
I will behave.
Please, please, please...
Okay, okay, fine,
you can come.
But don't tell
anybody else.
It's up on the roof
at 8:00.
A soap opera roof party?!
I'm going to a soap opera
roof party?!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
And it's out of my system.
( speaking slowly ):
And then my wife
and I went on a cruise
to the Galapagos.
There was a seafood buffet
you wouldn't believe.
There were clams...
and mussels...
and oysters...
and cracked crab...
and snow crab...
and king crab.
It's a pity
I'm allergic to shellfish.
So where did you get
your undergraduate degree?
And that's not all
I'm allergic to.
Oh, it's not over.
I'm also allergic
to peanuts and cashews
and almonds and filberts...
So, basically all nuts.
Interestingly, no.
Kind of playing it
fast and loose
with the word "interesting."
If you'll excuse me, I'm
going to use the restroom.
Oh, my God!
I've lost the will
to live.
Let's ditch him.
What?
Come on, while
he's still in
the bathroom.
I'm begging you.
Okay, okay, fine.
But I just have
one question for you.
( imitating Spafford ):
When we exit, should we
walk or run
or prance, or stroll...?
Stop it! Stop it!
He talks slow, but he
might pee fast, okay? Let's go.
Oh, hey, you guys,
this is Charlie.
Charlie, this is Phoebe
and my sister Monica.
Hi.
Charlie's going
to be joining my department.
Oh, you're a
paleontologist, too?
Oh, okay, now, what do you
think of Renyard's new theory
of species variegation
in segmented arthropods?
Well, I think he's
a little out there,
but he does have
some interesting ideas.
Uh-huh.
( phone ringing )
Oh, I'm sorry.
I have to take this.
Excuse me.
Renyard's theory
of species variegation?
Yeah, I saw the article
on your coffee table
and memorized the title
to freak you out.
So, did you two have fun?
Oh, my God,
she's-she's great.
I mean, we have
so much in common,
and she's just cool,
you know, and funny.
I don't know if you've noticed,
but she's a... ♪ hottie. ♪
♪ Hi. ♪
Hey. Hi, you guys.
Listen, you know what?
I'm not feeling
really well,
and I don't think I'm going
to get to go to the play.
Really? What's wrong?
I don't know.
I think it's kind of serious.
Um, you know, I was watching
this thing on TV this morning
about Newcastle Disease,
and I think I might have it.
Newcastle Disease is
a secretion-borne virus
that only affects chickens
and other poultry.
Okay, who's this?
I'm sorry. Rachel,
this is Charlie Wheeler.
She's a colleague.
Oh, hi.
I would shake your hand,
but I'm sure you don't want
to get my chicken disease.
Rachel, can I see
you for a second?
Sure.
You're not sick.
What? Yes, I am.
Okay, then why are you...
all dressed up?
Becau... when you're sick
you do whatever you can
to make yourself
feel better.
You just want to stay home
so you can make a move on Joey.
Oh, no, no.
I heard you before.
That is so not what this is.
Okay, then what is this?
Okay...
Joey is having a secret
Days of Our Lives party
up on the roof, and he sent
you guys to the play
to get rid of you.
What?!
What-what's going on?
Joey is having a secret
Days of Our Lives party
up on the roof.
And he didn't want
you guys to know about it,
but I came over here
to tell you.
I thought you came
to say you were sick.
All right, professor
or detective?
Wait. Joey's having
a party
and he wasn't going
to invite us?
Yeah, he does it
every year.
That's why he's sending
you to the play,
that's why he sent us
to that Medieval Restaurant
and to that button factory.
And that horrible museum tour?
No, I arranged that.
( knocking )
Hey, you guys, I'm turning in.
Have fun.
We know about your party,
Joey.
What party?
The game's over.
Take off your robe.
Okay, I mean...
No!
Close it up!
Close it!
Nice to meet you.
Hey, you made it.
All right.
Hey, glad you could make it.
Thanks for coming.
Oh, my God, Kyle Lowder.
Hi.
I love you!
Hey, that's why
I didn't invite you.
You have to calm down,
all right?
Just... go get yourself
a drink or something.
Oh, yeah, that's
what you want.
My inhibitions lowered.
Hey.
Oh, my God,
can you believe
we're surrounded by all this?
I can barely control myself.
Monica, you might
want to remember
that you're married.
Where is Chandler
anyway?
Oh, my God, Chandler.
Where the hell is everybody?
Why don't you like me?
Chapter One: My First Period.
Hey, Joey said
no autographs.
But if she's getting one,
I want one, too.
"To Monica," and none of
this "best wishes" crap.
I want "love."
Actually, Mon,
Matthew was giving me
his phone number.
Oh, man...
If I had known I was
coming to this party,
I never would've
gotten married.
It's nice to
meet you, Rachel.
Nice to meet you.
Call me.
We will.
Look at you,
with all the guys.
Guess you've forgotten
all about Joey.
Yeah, well.
I guess I have
forgotten about Joey.
And clearly, you've
forgotten about Chandler.
Oh, please.
Chandler's
the love of my life.
Whoa, leather pants.
Have mercy.
So, uh... it's probably
going to be hard
for you to leave
Boston, huh?
Actually, I'm kind of
happy to be leaving.
I just broke up
with someone.
Oh, so sad.
Still, it can't be easy
for you to leave Harvard.
Especially after
working alongside
a Nobel prize winner
like Albert Wintermeyer.
Actually, Albie's the
guy I broke up with.
You dated Albert Wintermeyer?
Yeah.
And you called him "Albie"?
I mean, that's like calling
Albert Einstein, uh...
Albie.
Yeah, well, he is
a brilliant man.
Ya think?
I mean, you went out with
the guy who
improved the accuracy
of radiocarbon dating
by a factor of ten.
Yes.
And while that is everything
one looks for in a boyfriend,
he had a lot of issues.
Oh, like what?
I'm sorry,
I don't mean to pry.
It's just that this must be
what regular people experience
when they watch
Access Hollywood.
Okay, you want the dirt?
Albie was seriously insecure.
I mean, he was really
intimidated by the guy
I dated before him.
Who's intimidating to a guy
who won the Nobel prize?
A guy who won two.
Two?
Don't tell me you dated
Benjamin Hobart?
Yeah, for three years.
Oh, my God.
Have you ever been in
a relationship with someone
who hasn't won
the Nobel prize?
No.
But there was my first
boyfriend Billy.
Oh, yeah, no Nobel prizes
for him?
No.
But he did just win the
MacArthur Genius Grant.
( snorts ):
What a loser.
Some more wine?
Hey, Ross.
Hey.
How's it going
with Charlie?
Oh, great.
After I finish my wine
I'm going to blow
my average-sized brains out.
What's the matter?
She only dates geniuses
and Nobel prize winners.
Oh, my God, at the Chinese
restaurant earlier today
I put chopsticks in my mouth
and pretended to be
a woolly mammoth.
I always loved that.
Of course you would, your brains
are smaller than mine.
I can't compete with the guys
she goes out with.
They're so out of my league.
Oh, my God.
Worse?
Oh, much, much worse.
I did my impression
of Joan Rivers
as one of the earliest
amphibians.
"Can we walk?"
( giggles )
Oh, you like that?
No.
What?
Come on.
I think that's funny.
Woolly mammoth.
Come on.
( applause )
Well, I bet you're
all thinking
that now would be
a really great time
for an intermission, huh?
( sighs ):
Oh, yes. God, yes.
Well, you're not going
to get one.
'Cause in life there are
no intermissions, people.
Now, Chapter Seven:
Divorce is a Four-Letter Word.
How could he leave me?!
I-I don't know, you seem lovely.
Hey, Ross.
This is one
of my co-stars, Dirk.
Dirk, this is
my good friend Ross.
Nice to meet you.
Hey.
So what show you on?
Oh, I'm not an actor.
I'm a professor
of paleontology.
That's science.
Oh.
Hey, well, listen,
I play a scientist on Days.
My character just won
a Nobel prize.
Hey, Ross, listen,
Dirk was wondering about
the woman that you brought.
And if you guys
are together or...?
Oh, um, well, no, but...
she only goes out with
really, really smart guys.
Hey, I got a 690
on my SATs.
I'd lead with that.
That's it, just sign
right on the bra.
Monica!
Don't worry, Joe,
I won't come next year.
What do you got there?
Oh, just some boys
gave me their phone numbers.
Really? Let me see.
Oh.
Damn, that's a lot of guys.
Are you a little slutty?
I think I am.
Let me see if I approve
of any of these clowns.
Oh, this guy wears a rug.
This guy's Canadian.
And this guy
is in a cult, okay?
It'll cost you $5,000
to get to level three.
And I don't feel
any different.
Pass... oh, pass.
Pass.
Why? Why? What's wrong
with these guys?
Well, nothing major.
It's just that, you know,
they're not really
good enough for you.
And you deserve the best.
Joey, you're so sweet.
It's true.
But it doesn't matter
because I already know
who you're going to
go home with tonight.
Who?
Me.
What?
Really?
Yeah, because
we live together.
It's a joke.
Oh, I get it!
Right, that's funny.
I get it.
Got ya.
You're funny, Joey.
( sighs )
So, how did you enjoy
the play?
Oh, my God, honey,
I am so, so, so,
so, so, so sorry.
Well, you should be.
You missed the most
powerful three hours
in the history
of the theater.
You really liked it?
Oh, yeah.
I mean, at first I hated it.
But why wouldn't I?
Because as a man, I've been
trained not to listen!
But after Chapter 16:
Fat, Single
and Ready to Mingle,
I was uplifted.
Wow, really?
Oh, yeah, I had no idea
of the amazing journey
you go through as a woman.
Tell me... tell me about
your first period.
No.
Did somebody sign your bra?
So I got it
when I was 13.
Very difficult and it...
Hey, Ross.
So, listen, about you
and the dinosaur girl...
Are you really
just going to let
a couple of Nobel prizes
scare you off?
What is that?
Come on, a piece of paper?
It's actually a
million dollar prize.
Go, Charlie.
But my point is...
okay, so she dated them,
but she also
broke up with them.
Maybe she's looking
to, you know,
slum it with
some average Joe PhD.
Yeah, maybe.
And I do have my whole
career in front of me.
I mean, I-I could still
win a Nobel prize.
Although, the last two
papers I've written
were widely discredited.
You're so much more
than just brains.
You are sweet
and kind and funny.
And sexy.
Okay, well, give her
a chance to see all that.
Yeah. Yeah.
You're right.
Thanks, Pheebs.
I'm going to go find her.
Good for you.
Hey, and I thought your paper
on punctuated equilibrium
in the Devonian Era
was top notch.
Stop going
through my stuff.
Hey.
I just wanted
to let you know,
I've changed my mind.
I'm going to do it,
I'm going to kiss Joey.
No. You can't.
Friends hooking up
is a bad idea.
Please, what about you
and Chandler?
That's different.
I was drunk and stupid.
Well, hello!
What about all the guys
that you got
the phone numbers from?
Why don't you just
kiss one of them?
I could, I could,
but I don't want to.
I want to kiss Joey.
All right.
I think it's a big mistake,
but it's your decision.
I'm going to do it.
And I can't stop you.
No.
Hey, Rach,
have you seen
Charlie anywhere?
I'm smarter than him!
Thank you so much for
these tickets, Chandler.
This was a really important
experience for me
and I wanted
to share it with you.
You're so wonderful.
Why don't you like me?
Chapter One: My First Period.
Can't believe you guys
bought that.
Enjoy your slow death.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGH
access.wgbh.org